<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Unearthed Arcana Allowed</name>
        <description>Uneatherd Arcana Allowed from The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014.</description>
        <author url="">RJBPrime</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="ua-bof-2014.xml" url="" />
        </update>
    </info>

<element name="Close Quarters Shooter" type="Class Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are trained in making ranged attacks at close quarters. When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you.
            You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ranged:attack" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Tunnel Fighter" type="Class Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TUNNEL_FIGHTER">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You excel at defending narrow passages, doorways, and other tight spaces. As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

        <!-- Fighting Style: Mariner -->
    <element name="Mariner" type="Class Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_MARINER">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" equipped="!([armor:heavy]||[shield:any])" />
            <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" equipped="!([armor:heavy]||[shield:any])" />
            <stat name="ac:misc" value="1" equipped="!([armor:heavy]||[shield:any])" />
        </rules>
    </element>

        <!-- Eldritch Invocations -->
    <element name="Kiss of Mephistopheles" type="Class Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_KISS_OF_MEPHISTOPHELES">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, eldritch blast cantrip</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:5],ID_PHB_SPELL_ELDRITCH_BLAST</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, eldritch blast cantrip</p>
            <p>When you hit a creature with your <i>eldritch blast</i>, you can cast <i>fireball</i> as a bonus action using a warlock spell slot. The spell must be centered on the creature you hit with <i>eldritch blast</i>.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you hit a creature with your <i>eldritch blast</i>, you can cast <i>fireball</i> as a bonus action using a warlock spell slot. The spell must be centered on the creature you hit with <i>eldritch blast</i>.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

        <!-- Martial Archetype: Brute -->
    <element name="Brute" type="Archetype" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_BRUTE">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Brutes are simple warriors who rely on mighty attacks and their own durability to overcome their enemies. Some brutes combine this physical might with tactical cunning. Others just hit things until those things stop hitting back.</p>
            <div element="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_BRUTE_FORCE"/>
            <div element="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_BRUTISH_DURABILITY"/>
            <div element="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_ADDITIONAL_FIGHTING_STYLE"/>
            <div element="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_DEVASTATING_CRITICAL"/>
            <div element="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_SURVIVOR"/>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/three-subclasses</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>Brutes are simple warriors who rely on mighty attacks and their own durability to overcome their enemies.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_BRUTE_FORCE" level="3"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_BRUTISH_DURABILITY" level="7"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_ADDITIONAL_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="10"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_DEVASTATING_CRITICAL" level="15"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_SURVIVOR" level="18"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Brute Force" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_BRUTE_FORCE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, you’re able to strike with your weapons with especially brutal force. Whenever you hit with a weapon that you’re proficient with and deal damage, the weapon’s damage increases by an amount based on your level in this class, as shown on the Brute Bonus Damage table.</p>
            <h5>BRUTE BONUS DAMAGE</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Fighter Level</td><td>Damage Increase</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>1d4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you hit with a weapon that you’re proficient with and deal damage, the weapon’s damage increases by 1d{{brute force:damage}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="brute force:damage" value="4" bonus="brute force" level="3" />
            <stat name="brute force:damage" value="6" bonus="brute force" level="10" />
            <stat name="brute force:damage" value="8" bonus="brute force" level="16" />
            <stat name="brute force:damage" value="10" bonus="brute force" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Brutish Durability" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_BRUTISH_DURABILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 7th level, your toughness allows you to shrug off assaults that would devastate others.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you make a saving throw, roll 1d6 and add the die to your saving throw total. If applying this bonus to a death saving throw increases the total to 20 or higher, you gain the benefits of rolling a 20 on the d20.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you make a saving throw, roll 1d6 and add the die to your saving throw total. If applying this bonus to a death saving throw increases the total to 20 or higher, you gain the benefits of rolling a 20 on the d20.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Additional Fighting Style" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_ADDITIONAL_FIGHTING_STYLE">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, you can choose a second option from the Fighting Style feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can choose a second option from the Fighting Style feature.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Additional Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Fighter" level="10"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Devastating Critical" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_DEVASTATING_CRITICAL">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 15th level, when you score a critical hit with a weapon attack, you gain a bonus to that weapon’s damage roll equal to your level in this class.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you score a critical hit with a weapon attack, you gain a +{{level:fighter}} bonus to that weapon’s damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Survivor" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRUTE_SURVIVOR">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level, you attain the pinnacle of resilience in battle. At the start of each of your turns in combat, you regain hit points equal to 5 + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 hit point). You don’t gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points or if you have more than half of your hit points left.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>At the start of each of your turns in combat, you regain {{survivor:hp}} hit points. You don’t gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points or if you have more than half of your hit points left.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="survivor:hp:mod" value="1" bonus="mod" />
            <stat name="survivor:hp:mod" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="mod" />
            <stat name="survivor:hp" value="5" />
            <stat name="survivor:hp" value="survivor:hp:mod" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Acrobat" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_ACROBAT">
        <description>
            <p>You become more nimble, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Acrobatics skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>As a bonus action, you can make a DC 15 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. If you succeed, difficult terrain doesn’t cost you extra movement until the end of the current turn.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can make a DC 15 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. If you succeed, difficult terrain doesn’t cost you extra movement until the end of the current turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_ACROBATICS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Animal Handler" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_ANIMALHANDLER">
        <description>
            <p>You master the techniques needed to train and handle animals. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Animal Handling skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You can use a bonus action on your turn to command one friendly beast within 60 feet of you that can hear you and that isn’t currently following the command of someone else. You decide now what action the beast will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you issue a general command that lasts for 1 minute, such as to guard a particular area.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can command one friendly beast within 60 feet of you that can hear you and that isn’t currently following the command of someone else. You decide now what action the beast will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you issue a general command that lasts for 1 minute, such as to guard a particular area.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_ANIMALHANDLING" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcanist" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_ARCANIST">
        <description>
            <p>You study the arcane arts, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You learn the <i>prestidigitation</i> and <i>detect magic</i> spells. You can cast <i>detect magic</i> once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast detect magic without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_ARCANA" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Brawny" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_BRAWNY">
        <description>
            <p>You become stronger, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Athletics skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You count as if you were one size larger for the purpose of determining your carrying capacity.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>You count as if you were one size larger for the purpose of determining your carrying capacity.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_ATHLETICS" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_WEIGHT_CAPACITY_COUNTS_AS_LARGER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Diplomat" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_DIPLOMAT">
        <description>
            <p>You master the arts of diplomacy, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>If you spend 1 minute talking to someone who can understand what you say, you can make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by the creature’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If you or your companions are fighting the creature, your check automatically fails. If your check succeeds, the target is charmed by you as long as it remains within 60 feet of you and for 1 minute thereafter.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you spend 1 minute talking to someone who can understand what you say, you can make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by the creature’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If you or your companions are fighting the creature, your check automatically fails. If your check succeeds, the target is charmed by you as long as it remains within 60 feet of you and for 1 minute thereafter.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Empathic" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_EMPATHIC">
        <description>
            <p>You possess keen insight into how other people think and feel. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You can use your action to try to get uncanny insight about one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you. Make a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by the target’s Charisma (Deception) check. If your check succeeds, you have advantage on attack rolls and ability checks against the target until the end of your next turn.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You can try to get uncanny insight about one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you. Make a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by the target’s Charisma (Deception) check. If your check succeeds, you have advantage on attack rolls and ability checks against the target until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INSIGHT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Historian" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_HISTORIAN">
        <description>
            <p>Your study of history rewards you with the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the History skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>When you take the Help action to aid another creature’s ability check, you can make a DC 15 Intelligence (History) check. On a success, that creature’s check gains a bonus equal to your proficiency bonus, as you share pertinent advice and historical examples. To receive this bonus, the creature must be able to understand what you’re saying.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take the Help action to aid another creature’s ability check, you can make a DC 15 Intelligence (History) check. On a success, that creature’s check gains a bonus equal to your proficiency bonus, as you share pertinent advice and historical examples. To receive this bonus, the creature must be able to understand what you’re saying.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_HISTORY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Investigator" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_INVESTIGATOR">
        <description>
            <p>You have an eye for detail and can pick out the smallest clues. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Investigation skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You can take the Search action as a bonus action.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can take the Search action as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INVESTIGATION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Medic" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_MEDIC">
        <description>
            <p>You master the physician’s arts, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>During a short rest, you can clean and bind the wounds of up to six willing beasts and humanoids. Make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check for each creature. On a success, if a creature spends a Hit Die during this rest, that creature can forgo the roll and instead regain the maximum number of hit points the die can restore. A creature can do so only once per rest, regardless of how many Hit Dice it spends.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>During a short rest, you can clean and bind the wounds of up to six willing beasts and humanoids. Make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check for each creature. On a success, if a creature spends a Hit Die during this rest, that creature can forgo the roll and instead regain the maximum number of hit points the die can restore. A creature can do so only once per rest, regardless of how many Hit Dice it spends.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_MEDICINE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Menacing" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_MENACING">
        <description>
            <p>You become fearsome to others, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack with an attempt to demoralize one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can’t be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Attack">
            <description>You can attempt to demoralize one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can’t be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INTIMIDATION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Naturalist" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_NATURALIST">
        <description>
            <p>Your extensive study of nature rewards you with the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Nature skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You learn the <i>druidcraft</i> and <i>detect poison and disease</i> spells. You can cast <i>detect poison and disease</i> once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast detect poison and disease without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_NATURE" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Perceptive" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_PERCEPTIVE">
        <description>
            <p>You hone your senses until they become razor sharp. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Perception skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>Being in a lightly obscured area doesn’t impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks if you can both see and hear.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Being in a lightly obscured area doesn’t impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks if you can both see and hear.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERCEPTION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Performer" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_PERFORMER">
        <description>
            <p>You master performance so that you can command any stage. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Performance skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>While performing, you can try to distract one humanoid you can see who can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Performance) check contested by the humanoid’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, you grab the humanoid’s attention enough that it makes Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks with disadvantage until you stop performing.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While performing, you can try to distract one humanoid you can see who can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Performance) check contested by the humanoid’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, you grab the humanoid’s attention enough that it makes Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks with disadvantage until you stop performing.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERFORMANCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Quick-Fingered" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_QUICKFINGERED">
        <description>
            <p>Your nimble fingers and agility let you perform sleight of hand. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Sleight of Hand skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>As a bonus action, you can make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check to plant something on someone else, conceal an object on a creature, lift a purse, or take something from a pocket.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check to plant something on someone else, conceal an object on a creature, lift a purse, or take something from a pocket.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Silver-Tongued" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_SILVERTONGUED">
        <description>
            <p>You develop your conversational skill to better deceive others. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Deception skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack with an attempt to deceive one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks from the target and your attack rolls against it have advantage; both benefits last until the end of your next turn or until you use this ability on a different target. If your check fails, the target can’t be deceived by you in this way for 1 hour.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Attack">
            <description>You can attempt to deceive one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks from the target and your attack rolls against it have advantage; both benefits last until the end of your next turn or until you use this ability on a different target. If your check fails, the target can’t be deceived by you in this way for 1 hour.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_DECEPTION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Stealthy" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_STEALTHY">
        <description>
            <p>You know how best to hide. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Stealth skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>If you are hidden, you can move up to 10 feet in the open without revealing yourself if you end the move in a position where you’re not clearly visible.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you are hidden, you can move up to 10 feet in the open without revealing yourself if you end the move in a position where you’re not clearly visible.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_STEALTH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Survivalist" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_SURVIVALIST">
        <description>
            <p>You master wilderness lore, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Survival skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You learn the <i>alarm</i> spell. You can cast it once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast alarm spell once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_SURVIVAL" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Theologian" type="Feat" source="The Book of Fantasia Campaign Guide 2014" id="ID_BOF14_FEAT_THEOLOGIAN">
        <description>
            <p>Your extensive study of religion rewards you with the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency in the Religion skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You learn the <i>thaumaturgy</i> and <i>detect evil and good</i> spells. You can cast <i>detect evil and good</i> once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast detect evil and good once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_RELIGION" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  </elements>
